educationmalaysia.gov.my 2015-11-20

# Privacy Policy

**EMGS Privacy Policy**  

We at EMGS, and our servants and agents, which means EMGS and its subsidiaries from time to time and their subsidiaries, ("we", "us", "our" or "EMGS" as the context requires) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with the terms of use of our website and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data or sensitive personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our policy regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. For the purpose of the Personal Data Protection Act 2010 (the Act) and this privacy policy:

"data user" is EMGS and/or any of EMGS subsidiaries, agents or servants from time to time.

"personal information" or “personal data” is any information about you, , including sensitive personal data which you provide to us, from time to time as set out in this privacy policy.

"application" is the process of applying for entry to courses offered by institutions of further and higher education which are accredited and licensed by the Government of Malaysia or the process for applying for permission to enter and remain in Malaysia as a student or the process for applying for permission to enter and remain in Malaysia as the spouse, parent or child of a Student. The application is processed by EMGS and third parties including government agencies. The application is updated with any revisions, including decisions from the higher education establishments and examination results received during the remainder of the application cycle.

“sensitive personal data” means any personal data consisting of information as to the physical or mental health or condition of a data subject, his political opinions, his religious beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, the commission or alleged commission by him of any offence or any other personal data as the Minister may determine by order published in the _Gazette_ ;

"Declaration" is the declaration which is currently accepted by the Institution on your behalf. You can read a copy of this declaration [ **here**](http://educationmalaysia.gov.my/skin/frontend/base/default/documents/T&C_THIRDPARTYSUBMISSIONOFSTUDENTAPPLICATIONv2.0.pdf). 

"website" is any of [www.educationmalaysia.gov.my](http://www.educationmalaysia.gov.my/) or https://stars.educationmalaysia.gov.my or any other website, RSS feed or any other website, RSS feed or phone application operated by us from time to time.  
  
---  
**1** | **Information which we collect about you**  
  | 1.1  | We may collect and process the following information about you:  
  |   | 

  1. Information which you provide to us from any of the input areas within the website.
  2. Information which you provide to us by any other means including (without limitation) telephone, fax or post.
  3. Information which you provide to us or the institution in connection with your application, which will be handled in accordance with this privacy policy and our data protection statement, which forms part of the declaration.
  4. If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

  |   |    
**2** | **How we use your personal information**  
  | 2.1  | We use personal information held about you in the following ways:  
  |   | 

  1. to process your application.
  2. to allow you to participate in any interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  3. to notify you about changes to our service.
  4. to ensure that content from our website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  5. to keep you informed (with your consent) by electronic means, or other means, of information about specific funding, sponsorship and products that we think may be of interest to you.
  6. to provide you (unless you object) with general information relevant to students.
  7. marketing related information (with your consent)

  | **** 2.2 | We may share personal information included in your application, or which you subsequently supply to us, with the staff of the institutions which (i) you have previously or currently attend as a student or (ii) you are making application to attend for further or higher education as indicated in your application; or (iii) consular representatives from your country of origin.  
  | 2.3  | The Malaysian Government requires prospective foreign students to submit applications for Student Passes through the Higher Education Institution (“the Institution”) upon acceptance on the course. This means the institution will be passing personal data and sensitive personal data to us for processing. EMGS assumes that the Institution will comply with the provisions of the Act in the handling of your data and EMGS disclaims any liability for any breach of the Act arising from the actions or failings of any Institution.  
  | 2.4  | EMGS or their authorized representatives, partners or subsidiaries will take all reasonable precautions to protect the security of your data however we cannot be liable to you for any loss or damage suffered by you as a result of an unauthorised third party having accessed your application.  
  | 2.5 | Where you use our website to submit an application, we may invite you to participate in surveys intended to assist us in the development of our services or for enhancement of areas of study in which you have expressed interest. Whilst your views will be welcome to us, there is no obligation for you to respond. You will be given details of the purpose of the survey and the parties who will undertake it.  
  | 2.6 | We may, on occasion, be required to undertake a check of your identity. This will be conducted in confidence. We will normally discuss this with you prior to carrying out any identity checks.  
  | 2.7 | EMGS will cooperate, where it is required to do so, with enquiries from authorities which demonstrate a legal requirement for access to information about you. These include, but are not limited to: Malaysian and International Police Forces, the Malaysian Department of Immigration, the Ministry of Higher Education and any other bona fide investigators on behalf of other agencies pursuing a lawful enquiry.  
  |   |    
**3** | **Communicating with you**  
  | 3.1 | The information we collect from you in connection with your application will include (without limitation) your name; postal and email address; and telephone numbers, both home and mobile. If any of these details change, it is important that you tell us straight away so that we can communicate with you about your application.  
  | 3.2 | We will normally communicate with you by electronic means in respect of any application made by you.  
  | 3.3 | You may contact us by any of the methods set out on our Contact us page of the website. If you have any questions about our use of your personal data, please write to the Data Protection Officer, EMGS, 20th Floor, Menara TA One, 22 Jalan P. Ramlee, Kuala Lumpur Malaysia 50250.  
  
  |   |    
**4** | **Commercial mailings from EMGS**  
  | 4.1  | From time to time we may use your personal information to send you general information ('Mailings') by post, email or SMS, such as (without limitation), information relating to career information (relevant to your chosen subjects). If you are unsuccessful in your application and become unplaced, we may send you information from education establishments who have spaces on courses available.  
  | 4.2  | In addition, from time to time, we would like to make use of your personal information to send you promotional information about (without limitation) products and services which may be of interest to you. Commercial mailings may include information sent by the EMGS Bhd on behalf of carefully selected third parties; these can include information on student discounts, travel, banking, and professional associations. Please note that except as set out in this privacy policy or data protection statement, your details will not be released to any third party.  
  | 4.3 | We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.  
  | 4.4  | If you do not wish your personal information to be used by us to send you third party mailings by post you must ensure that you tick the appropriate box on the registration page.  
  | 4.5  | If you wish to receive third party information by text, email or both you should tick the appropriate boxes on the registration page.  
  | 4.6 | You may, at any time, withdraw your permission for EMGS to use your personal information for the purposes of sending mailings by writing to the Data Protection Officer, EMGS, 20th Floor, Menara TA One, 22 Jalan P. Ramlee, Kuala Lumpur Malaysia 50250 by emailing us at [enquiry@emgs.com.my](mailto:enquiry@emgs.com.my) heading your email ‘Data Protection Notice’.  
  |   |    
**5** | **IP addresses, cookies and links**  
  | 5.1  | We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify you as an individual.  
  | 5.2  | EMGS may use cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data which is stored on your computer and which is revealed to EMGS when you use this network. EMGS uses cookies only to make it easier to identify you when using the network. EMGS does not use cookies to collect additional information about you. You can configure your web browser not to accept cookies, although this may hinder the functionality of the network for you.   
  | 5.3 | The website may contain links that make it easy for you to visit other websites. EMGS does not have any control over these websites. Therefore, if you use these links to leave EMGS and visit websites operated by third parties, EMGS cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide whilst visiting these websites.  
  |   |    
**6** | **Your right to ask to see the information we hold about you**  
  | 6.1  | Upon the coming into force of the Personal Data Protection Act 2010 you may request for us to provide you with details of personal information that we hold about you. If you want to make a request for this information you should write to EMGS at the address given in section 3.3 above. There will be a fee of RM10 payable to “EMGS Escrow Account 1”. A bank draft for this amount should be sent to EMGS with your request for information.  
  | 6.2 | If you request us to do so, we will consider making changes to the information that we hold about you. We will change certain limited information that we hold about you where you tell us it is incorrect. We cannot make any changes to information contained in your application such as (without limitation) your photograph, academic qualifications, medical health report or references. If you believe any such information is incorrect or contains any errors or mistakes, you must contact your selected higher education institutions directly to discuss these.
